A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1937-1938
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1937-1938
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.491, III
This collection consists of 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1937-1938
  - "A" Miscellaneous (Albemarle Agriculture Society meetings; Department of Agriculture Celebration; Wallace speech; Mrs. Alderman correspondence-- re: Life of Alderman; American Council on Education--minutes of meetings; Associated Clubs for Virginia--Billboard Bill; Lady Astor -correspondence re: gift of squash courts) 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alderman, Life of 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Correspondence of Tunstall re: founding of Alumni Board 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Investments 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Meeting 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Treasurer 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Board--Presidents Contingent Fund 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund (1 of 2) 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund (2 of 2) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Art--Annual Report 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Art--Bayly Art Museum (Indian Collection Gift; Annual Report) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Art--Hammarstrand Affair 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Articles on UVa. ( Cavalcade articles; Life pictures and article; statistics) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Astronomy (Cut in McCormick money; Report on Work of Department; Expedition with National Geographic Society; Enderberry Island Eclipse) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Athletics (Resigns from Southern Conference; correspondence of Beverley Tucker) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (UVa. Band--lack of support; A. Balz--semester calendar recommended; Stringfellow Barr--why he goes to Annapolis) 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Harry Byrd and J. S. Bryan--correspondence of 2 University Presidents) 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Biblical History and Literature 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake (new buildings) 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Rotunda 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Bursar (2 folders) (Report on investments of the Centennial Fund and Jefferson Memorial Fund of the University of Virginia, 1935) 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Bursar--Rotunda Restoration 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Cemetery--Report of Committee; Society of the Cincinnati--Report on Medal; College Topics--Petition; Committees of the Faculty--Administrative lists; College-- Committee Report; Corbitt, James H.--Correspondence--official and personal) 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - C.W.A. and P.W.A. 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Foundation and Carnegie Corporation 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Chemistry 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Church Society for College Work (call for meetings) 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Commerce and Business Administration 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Commons (should buy pasteurizing plant if possible) 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Convocations--(1937: speaker--W. A. Pott; 1938--speaker: Sir Wilmont Harsant Lewis) 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (Dobie, Armistead--Program for Recovery) 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Dean (Ferguson and Lewis)--General Agenda 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - DuPont Trust 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Education 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Engineering 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - English (Sadlier Collection of Gothic Romances and Tales of Terror) 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Extension 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Finals (1937--Stettinius Speech; 1938--Dumas Malone) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Finances 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Forestry (outline of plans for school on grounds of UVa.) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Forms 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Founder's Day (Ernest M. Hopkins) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - General Education Board (Rockefeller Fund--reports) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Geological Survey 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Geology 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - German 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - German Scholars--Emergency Committee on Aid of 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Gifts 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Governor's Office (correspondence concerning salary scale) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Graduate School (need of rooms) 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (Hampton History--recordings of ex-slaves; Sidney B. Hall--cooperation of state colleges, reciprocal relations with Havana; Oskar Hansen--Film Library service, desire to carve T.J. memorial; J.E.N. Hume--Memorial Fountain) 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - High School Visitations 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - History (suggested Commission on British Colonial Documents; Stringfellow Barr and his relationship to University of Chicago; re-grading final exams; resignation of R.H.Dabney; Reorganization of Dept. of History) 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Honor Courses--Committee report 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Honor System 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Hospital--Addition 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Hospital--UVa.--Ward Patient Statistics 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Institute of Public Affairs (2 folders)--correspondence of the Assistant Secretary of State--criticism of the Administration and the Institute; Death of Maphis; Gooch appointed as Director; Memorial to Maphis; Spencer Miller--speech, 1937) 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Insurance (Fine Arts for UVa.) 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - Interracial Cooperation--Virginia Commission (annuities; space in Library for Negro people; L. R. Reynolds correspondence) 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - Invitations to be represented 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - Invitations to be represented (2 folders) (Centennials, conferences, interracial meetings) 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation (report to Board of Governors) 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Jefferson--portrait 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Jefferson School of American Government (letters from supporters in Congress) 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Latin 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Law Department (Munford Boyd's recommendation; Alger Hiss to speak) 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Law School--General 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Law School--statistics 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Lectures--Page-Barbour 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Lectures--Richard 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Legal Papers (W. A. Perkins, attorney--annexation proceedings) 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Legal Papers (W. A. Perkins, attorney--"Estate of Conrad Hubert") 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Legal Papers (W. A. Perkins, attorney--Lizzie Miller Farm) 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Legislative Program (statement of certain urgent needs of UVa. to be presented to Governor Peery) 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Library--Alderman (contracts and specifications) (1 of 3) 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Library--General (2-3of 3) (Dumas Malone--speaker at dedication of Library; lists of dedication ceremony guests; Library Committee meeting minutes) 1937-1938 (Box 11)
  - Library--McGregor Library 1937-1938 (Box 11)
  - Library--Stone Collection 1937-1938 (Box 11)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (Chapin W. Maupin--gift of grandfather clock) 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - McIntire Fund--list of securities 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Mathematics 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department (outline of Student Health Service; Death of Dr. Neff and replacement suggestions) 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department--Hospital Addition funds 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department--Hospital, general 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical Department--Student Health Service (report of Dept. of Student health; 1st Annual Budget) 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Medical School (information for Ms. Lape, American Foundation) 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Mellon Trust 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Music 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (National Research Council--fellowships; National Association of State Universities; Hutchins-Dewey Clash) 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - National Youth Administration (placement statistics; Student Aid Program) 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - National Association of State Universities 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - National Association of University Presidents (criticisms of accrediting agencies) 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Negro Admissions and Scholarship Fund 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Patents Committee 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Personnel (survey papers) 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Philosophy 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Physical Education 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Physics (memorandum of work of department) 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Political Science 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Prospective Donors 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Psychology 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Public Administration, Bureau of 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Public Administration, Bureau of (Committee: Kincaid, Snavely, Ribble, Spicer, Egger) 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Public Speaking 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Questionnaires 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - "R" Miscellaneous (Raven Society--election speakers; Richardson, Eudora Ramsey--Charlottesville Manuscript, folklore, W.P.A.) 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Recommendations 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Religion 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Research, Committee on (Ivey Lewis, Chair; report) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Rhodes Fellowships and Scholarships (statistics; letters from Gooch) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Rockefeller Foundation 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Romance Languages 1937-1938 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Ryan Estate (portraits bequeathed to UVa.) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (3 folders) (Schwartz, A.--song "Virginia"; Seal of Virginia--records; Sigma Xi--President's and Visitors' prize; Slaughter, Jane--Letter about John Page; Slemp, C. Bascom-- collection of pictures and prizes; Southern Historical Association Quarterly--articles; Stettinius, E.--boxbushes) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Salaries 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Scholarship (Ryan--conditions) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Senate (Roads; elections) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Social Sciences, Institute for Research in (agenda) 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Sociology 1937-1938 (Box 15)
  - Southern University Conference 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - Speeches and Clippings 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - Statistics (conditions of UVa.) 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - Sullivan Foundation Award (history and description) 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - Summer Session (Maphis, Gooch--letters, registration) 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - "T" Miscellaneous (Bernard P. Taylor--Stone Collection; Tome School--reorganization recommendation; H. Trout--Rotunda restoration; Beverley Tucker--interest in students, Nuckols Scholarship; Robert Tunstall--Stone Library, McGregor Library) 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - University Houses 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1937-1938 (Box 16)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review(financial reports; change in editor [Davis to Lee]; Conditions of position offered; Annual reports) 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - Visitors--General (cement problem, Barnes Lumber contract) 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - Visitors--meetings (James L. Minor--scholarship; New library; Honor System--Meisel case; R. H. Dabney resignation; "Pantop") 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (William H. White--report to President on effect on Salaries of Supreme Court decision; J. E. Williams--"Preparation for College"; Frances M. Williams--Rembrandt Peale portrait of Jefferson; Jennings S. Wise--help for UVa. from Mr. Mellon; Wood, R. H.--moving Tablet) 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - White, William H.--Foundation Lectures 1937-1938 (Box 17)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous (Yale University--street traffic research) 1937-1938 (Box 17)